Guide to the Lauchlin Bernard Currie Papers, 1931-1994 and undated (bulk 1950-1990) RL.00277
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Printed Materials Series
  - Evaluacion de las metas de la politicamacroeconomica, Currie, 1986 November (Box 6)
  - El crecimiento con estabilidad y el fondomonetario internacional, Currie, undated (Box 6)
  - Preliminary Report on Some Aspects ofPublic Administration in Colombia, Currie (for World Bank), 1986 October 20 (Box 6)
  - Perspectivas para Santander delsur, Currie, Asesor General, Fundacion para el Progreso de Colombia, 1962 June (Box 6)
  - Informe sobre el departamento delmeta, dirigido por Currie, Sintesis del Estudio Economico sobre elDepartamento de Meta, 1962 July (Box 6)
  - El uso de nuestras tierras. Conferencia pronunciada en Barrancaber por el Professor Currie, 1962 August 19 (Box 6)
  - Varios aspectos de la planeacionnacional, Conferencia pronunciada en Medellin el 8 octubre de 1962por el ProfesorCurrie (Box 6)
  - Some Unresolved Issues in NationalProgramming, Address by Currie before the Third Congress of theColombian Society of Economists, 1963 (Box 6)
  - The Meat Industry in Colombia: A StudyContracted by the Ferrocarriles Nacionales, directed by Currie, Bogota,1961 September (Box 6)
  - Operacion Colombia: un programa nacionalde desarrollo economico y social, Currie, undated (Box 6)
  - "Urbanization: Some Basic Issues,"Currie, 1975 April 17 (Box 6)
  - "Algunas consideraciones sobre la industria de carne en Colombia," Currie, Bogota, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Parte I, Operacion Colombia, Segunda Edicion, Captilos I a IV, Currie, Ultimo Borrador, 1963 September (Box 6)
  - Parte II y III, OperacionColombia, Segunda Edicion, Capitulos V a IX, Currie. Ultimo Borrador, 1963 September (Box 6)
  - Asian Drama: An Inquiry into the Povertyof Nations, Vol. I. Gunnar Myrdal, 1968 (Box 6)
  - 'Asian Drama: An Inquiry into the Poverty of Nations,' Vol. III. Gunnar Myrdal, 1968 (Box 6)
  - Equality and Efficiency: The BigTradeoff, Arthur M. Okun, 1975 (Box 6)
  - Operacion Colombia: un programa nacionalde desarrollo economico y social, Currie, undated (Box 6)
  - World Development Report 1984, 1984 (World Bank.) (Box 6)
  - The Exchange Rate System, John Williamson. Institute for International Economics, 1983 September (Box 6)
  - Estudio de un proyecto sobre reservasinternacionales y reactivacion economica (Box 6)
  - Operacion Colombia typescript, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Private Sector Development and EnterpriseReforms in Growing Asian Economies, Seiji Naya, International Centerfor Economic Growth, 1990 (Box 7)
  - Economic Survey of Singapore 1987, Ministry of Trade and Industry, Republic of Singapore (Box 7)
  - Urbanization: Some Basic Issues, Currie, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Savings, Monetary Correction and Building:Essays on Interrelationships in Colombia, Currie, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Integration of National Economic and UrbanPhysical Planning, Lauchlin Currie, Prepared for Group of Experts onIntegration of Economic and Physical Planning, United Nations, 1973 August 22 (Box 7)
  - La politica urbana y el plan dedesarrollo, Departamento Nacional de Planeacion, 1974 January (Box 7)
  - Singapore - A Growth Economy, Currie, 1973 March 27 (Box 7)
  - Draft of Paper for London Conference, Seminar on NewTowns, Prepared by Currie, 1973February14 (Box 7)
  - Urbanization Trends and Polices, Currie, Interregional Seminar on New Towns, London, 1973 June 4 (Box 7)
  - Seminario interregional sobre nuevasciudades, Londres, 4 a19 de Junio, 1973, NacionesUnidas (Box 7)
  - What Colombia (and other developingcountries) May Learn From Singapore, Currie, 1973 March (Box 7)
  - The Concept and Significance of NationalProduct, Currie, 1972 November (Box 7)
  - Documento de trabajo sobre las bases delplan de desarrollo, 1971 August 26 (Box 7)
  - An Urban Policy for DevelopingCountries, Currie, 1971 August (Box 7)
  - Plan general de desarrollo, Currie, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Reorganizacion de la industriaganadera, Currie, 1962 September (Box 7)
  - La industria ganadera y la nacion, Currie, 1962 April (Box 7)
  - Un programa de desarrollo economico en laencrucijada, Currie, 1962 May (Box 7)
  - Bogota: Alternatives for UrbanDevelopment, directed by Currie, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Wants, Needs, and Welfare, Currie,1970 March Simon FraserUniversity Dept. of Economics and Commerce Working Paper (Box 7)
  - Reorganizacion del ministerio defomento, Currie, 1959 May (Box 7)
  - Boletin fiscal, Departamento Norte deSantander, 1962 May-August (Box 7)
  - Hearings before the Subcommittee to Investigate theAdministration of the Internal Security Act and Other Internal Security Law ofthe Committee on the Judiciary, United States Senate, Eighty-Second Congress, First Session on The Institute ofPacific Relations, Parts 1-12, 1951 (13 folders) (Box 7)
  - Operacion Colombia, un programa nacionalde desarrollo economico y social, Currie, 1961 May (Box 7)
  - Hearings cont., S. Res. 366 (Box 8)
    - Part 13 (Box 8)
    - Part 14 (Box 8)
    - Part 30 (Box 8)
  - Estudio de desarrollo urbano de Bogota,Apendice 3: analisis financiero, 1975 January (Box 8)
  - Review and Conclusions, 1982-1984 (Box 8)
  - The Timing and Sequencing of a TradeLiberalization Policy: Colombia 1967-82, Jorge Garcia Garcia, Bogota, 1986 April (Box 8)
  - Medicion del deficit del secto publicocolombiano y su financiacion, 1950-1986, Jorge GarciaGarcia (Box 8)
  - Problems of Trade Liberalization inColombia, Jorge Garcia Garcia, Bogota, 1984 August (Box 8)
  - Estrategia: economica yfinanciera, article on Currie, 1994 Febuary18 (Box 8)
  - Funcion social de una universidad, Currie, 1963 December (Box 8)
  - Cuadernos de economia: UniversidadNacional de Colombia, homenage a Currie, 1993 (2copies) (Box 8)
  - Proposed System of Accounting For andControl Of Public Finances and Properties (Box 8)
  - Reflections on Colombian AgriculturalPolicy, Currie, 1962 March (Box 8)
  - Member Bank Reserves and BankDebits (Box 8)
  - Fundacion para el progreso de Colombia, ANational Program for a Critical Period, An Address Delivered by Currieat the Annual Meeting of the Chamber of Commerce of Colombia, 1962 May 25 (Box 8)
  - Notes and Discussions on The Decline of the CommercialLoan (Box 8)
  - Member Bank Indebtedness and Net DemandDeposits in the Federal Reserve System (Box 8)
  - Implications of Raising Productivity inAgriculture (Box 8)
  - Money, Gold, and Income in the UnitedStates: 1921-32, Currie, 1933 November (Box 8)
  - Republic of Colombia: 1985-86 FinancingPlan (Box 8)
  - Documento de discusion sobre la politicamacroeconomica y financiera colombiana, 1985 (Box 8)
  - Palabras del Senor David Knox, El BancoMundial en Centroamerica, 1984 November29 (Box 8)
  - World Bank Staff Report on September 27,1984, 1984 September (Box 8)
  - External Debt and MacroeconomicPerformance in Latin America and East Asia, Jeffrey Sachs (Box 8)
  - El comportamiento del sector agricola enlos Estados Unidos en los Pasados cincuenta y cinco anos (Box 8)
  - Algunos comentarios sobre las cifrasagricolas de los Estados Unidos, 1989 September19 (Box 8)
  - El comportamiento del sector agricolo enlos Estados Unidos... 1985 October 3 (Box 8)
  - Some Comments on the U.S. AgriculturalFigures, 1989 September18 (Box 8)
  - Notes on Material Prepared by David Wall and Harold Dunkerley on Coffee in Colombia, 1967 July 29 (Box 8)
  - Misión de administracion publica: Volume1-2, Currie, Bogota (Box 8)
  - Programacion financiera aplicada: El casode Colombia, Instituto del FMI (Box 8)
  - Taming the Megalopolis: A Design for UrbanGowth, Lauchlin Currie, 1976(2 copies) (Box 9)
  - Urban Policy in the Context ofDevelopment, Fifth Pacific Regional Science Conference, Currie,Vancouver, 1977 August 16 (Box 9)
  - External Debt and MacroeconomicPerformance in Latin America and East Asia, Jeffrey D. Sachs (Box 9)
  - Programa de construccion y reconstruccionde carreteras nacionales de la republica de Colombia, 1951-54 (2copies) (Box 9)
  - Some Aspects of Local GovernmentFinances, Dick Netzer (Box 9)
  - Accession #1998-0349
    - Articles; Biography (Box 9)
    - Memos and Reports, 1935-1938 (Box 9)
    - Clippings, 1937-1938 (Box 9)
    - Clippings - Book Reviews, 1990s (Box 9)
    - Clippings - Obituaries (Currie), 1993-1994 and undated (Box 9)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1994 and undated (Box 9)
  - Accession #1999-0172
    - Correspondence, 1945-1992 (Box 9)
    - House Committee on Un-American Activities statement, 1951 (Box 9)
- Personal Papers Series
  - Economic Theory, 1945-1974 (2 folders) (Box 10)
  - Agriculture, 1955-1976 (2 folders) (Box 10)
  - Fiscal, 1946-1993 (5 folders) (Box 10)
  - Exchange Rate (Box 10)
  - Development, 1960-1990 (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - Distribution, 1955-1974 (Box 11)
  - Population, 1959-1970 (Box 11)
  - Macroeconomic Policy, 1951-1992 (Box 11)
  - Macroeconomic Policy, 1951-1992 (total 12 folders) (Box 12)
  - Growth, 1950-1960 (4 folders) (Box 12)
  - Growth, 1971-1979 (9 folders) (Box 12)
  - Growth, 1980-1984 (6 folders) (Box 12)
  - Growth, 1985-1987 (8 folders) (Box 13)
  - Growth, 1988 (8 folders) (Box 13)
  - Growth, 1989 (Box 13)
  - Growth, 1989 (total 6 folders) (Box 14)
  - Growth, 1990 (10 folders) (Box 14)
  - Growth, 1991-1993 (2 folders) (Box 14)
  - China, 1940-1944 (24 folders) (Box 14)
  - China, 1940-1993 (2 folders) (Box 15)
  - UPAC, 1971-1972 (6 folders) (Box 15)
  - UPAC, 1973 (17 folders) (Box 15)
  - UPAC, 1974-1976 (4 folders) (Box 16)
  - UPAC, 1981-1983 (Box 16)
  - UPAC, 1983 (2 folders) (Box 16)
  - UPAC, 1984 (2 folders) (Box 16)
  - UPAC, 1985 (2 folders) (Box 16)
  - UPAC, 1986 (4 folders) (Box 16)
  - UPAC, 1987 (Box 16)
  - UPAC, 1988 (3 folders) (Box 16)
  - UPAC, 1989 (2 folders) (Box 16)
  - UPAC, 1990 (5 folders) (Box 16)
  - UPAC, 1980s and 1990 (Box 17)
  - Housing - Urban, 1959-1993 (Box 17)
  - Housing - Urban, 1959-1993 (total 23 folders) (Box 18)
  - Fundavi, 1974-1984 (Box 18)
  - Articles by Currie (Box 18)
  - Articles by Currie (Box 19)
  - Memos, 1962-1964 (5 folders) (Box 19)
  - Books (Box 19)
  - Books (total 6 folders) (Box 20)
  - Talks, Speeches, and Prologues (4 folders) (Box 20)
  - Distinctions and Forum (4 folders) (Box 20)
  - Teaching (Box 20)
  - Teaching (total 12 folders) (Box 21)
  - Money, 1930s to 1990s (5 folders) (Box 21)
  - Money, 1971-1976 (Box 21)
  - Money, 1975-1976 (16 folders) (Box 21)
  - Money, 1977-1981 (2 folders) (Box 21)
  - Money, 1982-1985 (Box 21)
  - Money, 1986-1987 (Box 21)
  - Money, 1988-1989 (Box 21)
  - Growth, 1970-1971 (12 folders) (Box 21)
  - Money, 1971-1976 (Box 22)
  - 1970-1971 (Box 22)
  - Money, 1990-1991 (Box 22)
  - 1970-1971 (4 folders) (Box 23)
  - 1971-1972 (12 folders) (Box 23)
  - 1972 (14 folders) (Box 24)
  - 1972-1973 (9 folders) (Box 24)
  - 1973 (Box 24)
  - 1973 (total 20 folders) (Box 25)
  - 1973-1974 (Box 25)
  - 1973-1974 (total 21 folders) (Box 26)
  - 1974 (29 folders) (Box 26)
  - 1974-1975 (6 folders) (Box 27)
  - 1975 (19 folders) (Box 27)
  - 1976 (5 folders) (Box 28)
  - 1977 (4 folders) (Box 28)
  - 1978 (3 folders) (Box 28)
  - 1971-1976 (5 folders) (Box 28)
  - 1979 (6 folders) (Box 28)
  - 1971-1976 (7 folders) (Box 29)
  - 1980-1990 (Box 29)
  - 1980-1990 (total 11 folders) (Box 30)
  - Public Administration, 1980s (Box 30)
  - Washington Trip, 1985-1990 (2 folders) (Box 30)
  - Social Security, 1980s (Box 30)
  - 1963-1964 (Box 30)
  - 1963-1964 (total 22 folders) (Box 31)
  - 1965 (16 folders) (Box 31)
  - 1966-1969 (Box 31)
  - 1966-1969 (total 22 folders) (Box 32)
  - Graphics and Statistics, 1980-1990 (Box 32)
  - 1948-1953 (Box 32)
  - 1948-1953 (total 11 folders) (Box 33)
  - Operación Colombia (Box 33)
  - Operación Colombia (total 13 folders) (Box 34)
  - 1957-1962 (Box 34)
  - 1957-1962 (total 40 folders) (Box 35)
  - Comments on Books (Box 35)
  - Development, 1966-1990 (Box 35)
  - Notes on Growth (Box 35)
  - Other Papers (Box 35)
  - 1930s Articles (4 folders) (Box 35)
  - William Alanson White Psychiatric Foundation, 1945-1950 (Box 35)
  - (Currie was a trustee and member of editorialboard) (Box 35)
  - 1957-1962 (Box 35)
  - 1972 (Box 35)
  - 1972 (total 16 folders) (Box 36)
  - 1972-1973 (8 folders) (Box 36)
  - Allyn Young, 1925-1993 (5 folders) (Box 36)
  - Growth, 1991-1993 (Box 36)
  - Growth, 1991-1993 (total 7 folders) (Box 37)
  - Clippings (Box 37)
  - Clippings, 1947-1962 (Box 38)
  - Clippings, 1962-1965 (Box 39)
  - Clippings, 1965-1974 (Box 40)
  - Graphics and Statistics, 1980-1990 (oversize) (Box 41)
  - Graphics and Statistics, 1980-1990 (oversize) (Box 42)
- Accession 2000-0251
  Scope and Contents note
  This addition to the collection contains copies of correspondence and writings by Currie, as well as transcripts and other documents related to the investigation of Currie by the House Un-American Activities Committee. Most items are photocopies and were used by Professor Roger J. Sandilands for his article, Guilt by Association? Lauchlin Currie's Alleged Involvement with Washington Economists in Soviet Espionage, to be published in Fall 2000. A typescript of the article is also included.
  - Acc. 00/251 (Box 43)
- Accession (2003-0208), 1 box
  The addition contains primarily correspondence between Currie and his biographer, Roger Sandilands, and related material about Currie's contributions to development economics (1992-1993). Includes comments on Currie's views and on the writings and positions of other economists.
  - Acc. 03/208 (Box 44)
- Accession (2012-0051), 6 boxes
  Currie's subject files, chiefly related to Colombian economy. Materials in Spanish. File folders have numeric codes assigned; some numbers are missing.
  - Ca. 1410-1453 (Box 45)
  - Ca. 1454-1459 (Box 46)
  - Ca. 1289, Ca. 1145-1154; Ca. 1155-1158, Ca. 1162-1163 (Box 47)
  - Ca. 1260-1266; Ca. 1268-1275, Ca. 1277-1286, Ca. 1288, Ca. 1159-1161, Ca. 1164 (Box 48)
  - Ca. 1165-1175; Ca. 1176-1179 (Box 49)
  - Ca. 1225, Ca. 1240-1244; Ca. 1226-1230, Ca. 1232-1239 (Box 50)
- Accession (2013-0009), 4 boxes
  - Ca. 1004-1012, Ca. 1014, Ca. 1050 (Box 51)
  - Ca. 1051-1054, Ca. 1056-1064, Ca. 1065 (Box 52)
  - Ca. 1067-1068, Ca. 1125-1132 (Box 53)
  - Ca. 1133-1144 (Box 54)
- Accession (2013-0179; 2014-0035), 5 boxes
  Currie's subject files and correspondences with scholars, chiefly related to Colombian economy. Materials in Spanish. File folders have numeric codes assigned; some numbers are missing.
  - Ca. 1025-1035, Ca. 1085-1093 (Box 55)
  - Ca. 1094-1105, Ca. 1107-1110, Ca. 1112-1124 (Box 56)
  - Ca. 1036-1047, Ca. 1049 (Box 57)
  - Ca. 1291-1298, Ca. 1300-1301, Ca. 1303-1310 (Box 58)
  - Ca. 1311-1314, Ca. 1316-1322, Ca. 1325-1326, Ca. 1328-1329, Ca. 1332, Ca. 1335-1337 (Box 59)
- Accession (2015-0014), 1 box
  Scope and Contents
  Currie's subject files and correspondences with scholars, chiefly related to Colombian economy. Some materials in Spanish. File folders have numeric codes assigned; some numbers are missing.
  - Ca. 1077 (Box 62)
  - Ca. 1078 (Box 62)
  - Ca. 1079, 1987 (Box 62)
  - Ca. 1080, 1964 (Box 62)
  - Ca. 1081 (Box 62)
  - Ca. 1082 (Box 62)
  - Ca. 1083 (Box 62)
  - Ca. 1084 (Box 62)